Guide to the William Smith Mason Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
William Smith Mason autograph collection
1800-1929
MS 344
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The collection consists of autograph manuscripts, documents and correspondence of people in public life. The collection contains correspondence of Theodore Roosevelt with Francis J. Heney and others and copies of letters of the Jonathan Knight family.
Mason, William Smith, 1866-
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The William Smith Mason Collection consists of manuscripts, documents, and correspondence of persons in public life, collected by William Smith Mason. Presidents, Cabinet members, Ministers to foreign countries, members of Congress, Generals, and other well-known persons during the years 1800-1924 are included. There are also copies of the papers of the Abel Knight Family of Eastbethlehem, Pennsylvania.
The William S. Mason Collection was a gift of the Kingsley Trust Association
Biographical / Historical
William Smith Mason was born in Millburn, Illinois in December, 1866. He received his Ph.B. from Yale in 1888 and his M.A. in 1924. Mason was active in the real estate and insurance business. He was the owner of a large collection of materials relating to Benjamin Franklin and a library of Revolutionary literature. Mason died in January, 1961.
Other Finding Aids
For an index of autograph letters in the William S. Mason collection, please consult the Autograph Index.
Engineering; Politicians -- Autographs; United States -- Politics and government; Autographs; Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844; Blaine, James Gillespie, 1830-1893; Calhoun, John C. (John Caldwell), 1782-1850; Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866; Chase, Salmon P. (Salmon Portland), 1808-1873; Clay, Henry, 1777-1852; Cleveland, Grover, 1837-1908; Douglas, Stephen A. (Stephen Arnold), 1813-1861; Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885; Heney, Francis Joseph, 1859-1937; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845; Knight, J. (Jonathan), 1787-1858; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865; Mason, William Smith, 1866-; McKinley, William, 1843-1901; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Seward, William H. (William Henry), 1801-1872; Sherman, John, 1823-1900; Stevens, Thaddeus, 1792-1868; Sumner, Charles, 1811-1874; Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862; Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852; Welles, Gideon, 1802-1878
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  (*) An index to these autograph letters is available in the repository.
  Contact Manuscripts and Archives for assistance.
  - 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Theodore Roosevelt: correspondence with Francis J. Heney and others, 1906-08 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Theodore Roosevelt: correspondence with Francis J. Heney and others, 1910-12 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Theodore Roosevelt: correspondence with Francis J. Heney and others, 1913-18 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Jonathan Knight family: letters (copies), 1820-91 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Other autograph letters (*) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1800-10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1811, 1819 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1824-28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1830-36 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1838-50 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1852-59 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1864-69 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1874-89 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1895-1901, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1924-29 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous letters and papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)